BRAC Memorabilia 5488 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
BRAC Memorabilia
1891-1964
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employees (BRAC)
5488 MB
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Correspondence, constitutions, memorabilia.
Constitutions, correspondence, membership cards, and a handkerchief
5657046
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 07, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 14, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees was organized in 1899, and it was the largest single railroad organization for employees who devoted a majority of their time to clerical work of any description including chief clerks, foremen, train announcers, gatemen, checkers; parcel, baggage, and storeroom employees; dock and pier workers; train and engine crew callers; timekeepers; paymasters; freight inspectors; rate and tariff compilers; weigh masters; ticket clerks and sellers; operators of all office and station equipment devices; telephone and switchboard operators; and all employees occupying or performing duties similar to those mentioned. After three months of experience in clerical work employees of both genders, with good moral character, became eligible for membership. The union secured increases in wages and better working conditions for its members.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5082: U.S. National Mediation Board Transcript of Hearings Regarding the BRAC 5086: U.S. National Mediation Board Transcripts Regarding New York Central Railroad Company and BRAC 5488: BRAC Records 5488 A: BRAC Chicago Files 5488 A & B mf: BRAC Guides on Microfilm 5488 B: BRAC Records 5488 C: BRAC Additional Records 5488 D: BRAC Additional Records 5735: BRAC Additional Records 6187: BRAC, Philadelphia Division, Union Local President Robert Curran Papers
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.; Order of Railroad Telegraphers (U.S.)
5657046
- Constitution - Order of Railroad Telegraphers (1891-1899) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Constitution - Order of Railroad Telegraphers (1900-1909) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Constitution - Order of Railroad Telegraphers (1911-1919) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Constitution - Order of Railroad Telegraphers (1921-1924) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Constitution - Order of Railroad Telegraphers (1927-1933) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Constitution - Order of Railroad Telegraphers (1936-1946) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Constitution - Order of Railroad Telegraphers (1952-1964) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ritual of the Order of Railroad Telegraphers (1893-1921) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- The Standard Code of Operating rules (1949); Use of extra employees (1952), 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- The Order of Railroad Telegraphs - Membership Cards (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence - To Telegraphers and Signalmen Employed on the Pennsylvania Railroad, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  photocopy and original (ripped)
- Correspondence - To All Members Employed on the Pennsylvania Railroad, Lines East of Pittsburg and Erie, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  photo copy and original (ripped)
- Railroad Brotherhood - handkerchief (navy and white) (Box 2, Folder 6)